<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Daniel Santiago-Rodríguez</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2018-04-28T17:00:13-04:00</updated><entry><title>Bcalaito pentester finally writes the setup tutorial</title><link href="/bcalaito-pentester-finally-writes-the-setup-tutorial.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-28T17:00:13-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-28T17:00:13-04:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Santiago</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-28:/bcalaito-pentester-finally-writes-the-setup-tutorial.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After giving a talk I promised the students that attended that I was going to write a tutorial on how to setup the lab exactly as I had it so they could test what I did. After almost two weeks I finally did. &lt;a href="http://bacalaitopentester.com/pages/mr-robot-lab-setup.html"&gt;Go here&lt;/a&gt; to setup the lab and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After giving a talk I promised the students that attended that I was going to write a tutorial on how to setup the lab exactly as I had it so they could test what I did. After almost two weeks I finally did. &lt;a href="http://bacalaitopentester.com/pages/mr-robot-lab-setup.html"&gt;Go here&lt;/a&gt; to setup the lab and to get the other instructions go to my &lt;a href="http://bacalaitopentester.com/bacalaito-pentester-gives-a-workshop.html"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; so you can download my writeup and get the 3 keys for the VM. If you get stuck you can always contact me. I hope you enjoy and teach someone else what you learn. &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Bacalaito pentester gives a workshop</title><link href="/bacalaito-pentester-gives-a-workshop.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Santiago</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-16:/bacalaito-pentester-gives-a-workshop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I was invited by my friend to give a talk at the university from which I graduated. I hate public speaking but I love cybersecurity so much that I do to just to teach the things I've learned along the way. I like to consider my self as an …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I was invited by my friend to give a talk at the university from which I graduated. I hate public speaking but I love cybersecurity so much that I do to just to teach the things I've learned along the way. I like to consider my self as an active member of the cybersecurity club for the Department of Computer Science of the University of Puerto Rico, Río Piedras Campus even though I don't attend the meetings. I gave a few workshops as a student. I decided to recycle a really cool workshop that I gave when I was a student to motivate new members with cybersecurity since it's really flashy with simple but effective techniques that are easy to learn. I use the &lt;a href="https://www.vulnhub.com/entry/mr-robot-1,151/"&gt;"Mr-Robot: 1"&lt;/a&gt; virtual machine from vulnhub.com. I'm a little nervous since it's been a long time since I've given a talk and because I think most of the people from the club won't know me. I decided to post the writeup for the exercise but since the python markdown extension is giving me a headache (it doesn't support nested code blocks) I exported the markdown to a pdf available &lt;a href="/pdfs/mrR0b0+.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I should write a post on how to setup the workshop but the horrors that I've endured working on this workshop have given me nightmares and I don't want to think about it for a while (note to self: don't wait 2 days before the workshop to prepare, specially if you haven't updated the laptop you're going to use for about a year because everything will go wrong  **wait for a future post** )&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Start of the Bacalaito Pentester's Journey</title><link href="/bacalaito-pentester.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-02T19:22:52-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-02T19:22:52-04:00</updated><author><name>rarFood</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-02:/bacalaito-pentester.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In spanish we use the word "bacalao" which means cod fish, in a somewhat derogatory way. This means that the author is putting himself down right off the bat. My name is Daniel Santiago. I would like to say that I am a security enthusiast. I enjoy most things related …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In spanish we use the word "bacalao" which means cod fish, in a somewhat derogatory way. This means that the author is putting himself down right off the bat. My name is Daniel Santiago. I would like to say that I am a security enthusiast. I enjoy most things related to cyber security. I've wanted to start a blog since a few years ago (check my github to see the first time i commited the welcom.gd for my page, it's sad) but I never got the courage to start posting up until now. I don't guarantee that I'll keep posting regularly but I think this is the first step. I intend to write about my experiences as a "bacalao" working as a pentester and the techniques I learn along the way. Maybe think of this blog as my public digital journal.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>